{"Topic": "Ancient Indian Texts", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Amuktamalayada is a book written by", "op1": "Harshavardhana", "op2": "Sri Krishna Deva Raya", "op3": "Bana Bhatta", "op4": "Rajendra Chola", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The book which gives an account of how Chandragupta Maurya overthrew the power of the Nandas with the help of Kautilya.", "op1": "Arthashastra", "op2": "Rajataringini", "op3": "Amuktamalayada", "op4": "Mudra Rakshasa", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The book which deals with the history of Kashmir from the earliest times to 1150 A.D.", "op1": "Rajataringini", "op2": "Ratnavali", "op3": "Mrichchakatikam", "op4": "Kumar Sambhava", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Prashnottar Ratna Malika, a treatise on eternal values of life in Hinduism has been authored by -", "op1": "Adi Shankaracharya", "op2": "Manu", "op3": "Bhrigu Samhita", "op4": "Rajatarangini", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the ancient Indian scholars calculated the exact value of pi?", "op1": "Varahamira", "op2": "Bhaskaracharya", "op3": "Brahmagupta", "op4": "Aryabhatta", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The famed Betal Pachisi is a part of which of the following books?", "op1": "Panchatantra", "op2": "Kathasaritsagar", "op3": "Mudra Rakshsasha", "op4": "Hitopadesha", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following books is based on a story appearing in the beginning of Mahabharata?", "op1": "Mudra Rakshasha", "op2": "Malvikagnimitra", "op3": "Geet Govinda", "op4": "Abhigyan Shakuntalam", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Padmavat, the book on the life of Padmini, Queen of Chittor, is written by", "op1": "Vishnu Sharma", "op2": "Chand Bardai", "op3": "Kalhana", "op4": "Malik Mohd Jaysi", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The book which deals with the love plays of the Dark Lord Krishna and his fair beloved Radha.", "op1": "Geet Govinda", "op2": "Meghdoot", "op3": "Padmavat", "op4": "Raghuvamsa", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following books has not been written by a king?", "op1": "Amuktamalayada", "op2": "Babar-Namah", "op3": "Ratnavali", "op4": "Harsha Charita", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following books is a treatise on economics and politics written by Chanakya?", "op1": "Natyashastra", "op2": "Arthashastra", "op3": "Ashtadhyayi", "op4": "Aryabhatiya", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who among the following was a Sanskrit grammarian and author of Ashtadhyayi?", "op1": "Patanjali", "op2": "Panini", "op3": "Manu", "op4": "Kalidasa", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Malavikagnimitra, a book based on the life of Agnimitra son of Pushyamitra Sunga, is written by", "op1": "Kalidasa", "op2": "Visakha Dutta", "op3": "Jaidev", "op4": "Chanakya", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following books is the foundational book of Sanskrit grammar?", "op1": "Mahabhasya", "op2": "Ashtadhyayi", "op3": "Meghdootam", "op4": "Bhrigu Samhita", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "He was an ancient Indian surgeon, also known as the \u2018Father of Surgery\u2019.", "op1": "Charaka", "op2": "Sushruta", "op3": "Patanjali", "op4": "Vatsayana", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following books dwells upon various surgeries and surgical instruments?", "op1": "Charaka Samhita", "op2": "Bhrigu Samhita", "op3": "Sushruta Samhita", "op4": "Rajatarangini", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the author-book combination is not correct?", "op1": "a and b only", "op2": "a, b and c", "op3": "c only", "op4": "None of the above", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following is credited with the introduction of decimal system?", "op1": "Aryabhatta", "op2": "Bhaskaracharya", "op3": "Varahamira", "op4": "Kautilya", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a collection of fables explaining the principles of life?", "op1": "Panchatantra", "op2": "Kathasaritsagar", "op3": "Jataka tales", "op4": "Arthashastra", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following books has not been written by Kalidasa?", "op1": "Raghuvamsa", "op2": "Meghdoot", "op3": "Kumar Sambhava", "op4": "Geet Govinda", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who among the following wrote \u2018Mahabhashya\u2019 a comment on Sanskrit book Ashtadhyayi?", "op1": "Patanjali", "op2": "Kalidasa", "op3": "Kalahana", "op4": "Chanakya", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who among the following is the author of the book \u2018Prithviraj Raso\u2019?", "op1": "Bana Bhatt", "op2": "Chand Bardai", "op3": "Todar Mal", "op4": "Mirabai", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Kamandaka's Nitisara is a contribution to:", "op1": "Logic and Philosophy", "op2": "Mathematics", "op3": "Political morality", "op4": "Grammar", "Answer": 1}]}